Lê Nguyễn Đăng Khoa

109/13A Huỳnh Thị Hai, Ward Tân Chánh Hiệp, District..12

८ 0934995729 **☑** leekhoa993@gmail.com **%** https://fb.com/leekhoa.lenguyendangkhoa

INTRODUCTION

I'm a System Engineer, specialized in Linux operating system. I have more than 6 years of work experience in System Engineering and Administration (both infrastructure/networking and IT applications). Currently, I work as a DevOps to automate infrastructure/system on-cloud. I have knowledge of integrating automation build, test, and deploying applications into Jenkins CI/CD. I have experience and strong at System Linux and other systems using Docker.

I like to research and work with new systems and new technologies. I always use my free time to learning new technologies and research them. I having a huge passion for Linux and the open-source community, enthusiastically, progressive. I'm interesting and focusing research on Linux systems, I hope I can become a good DevOps engineer.

EDUCATION

FPT JETKING 09/2013 - 09/2015

Network infrastructure management (Network and hardware)

Grade A. Average score 7.

- I have studied and researched networks, hardware, and little about language programming. I have archived high results in my learning process.
- Project learned: CCNA, LPI 1,2& advance, Firewall,...
- My graduation project is a design network and server system for medium enterprises, it is rated quite well in terms of ideas and techniques.

Nguyễn Tất Thành University

09/2011 - 09/2014

Infomation Technology

WORK EXPERIENCE

TMA Solution 02/2021 - Now

Senior System (DevOps).

Join Project - Network management system (Cloud solution).

- This project focuses on providing a multi-tenant cloud solution for NMS network management system.
- Build up tools and services for system monitoring and CI/CD.
- Build & configuration datapond with source code ParseDashboard.
- Implement and maintaining CI/CD leading to an improvement in the time to ship new feature releases.
- Write and edit script automation to upgrade & downgrade tenants.
- Deploy instance in AWS EC2 when have requested.
- Support customer/dev/QA solving issues about tenants, docker platform,.....

Join Project - Application component management (On-Premise solution).

- Working on 5G-Oran technology.
- Define stage and step in pipeline to build/test/deliver each component.
- Create a job in Jenkins to CI/CD for each component.
- Monitor and send mail alert of process Jenkins to email.

VNG Cloud 05/2018 - 02/2021

System Engineer (SysOps)

Join support, build, manage, monitor server for all systems of product VNG: Server Game, Storage, Zalo Team, system IT helpdesk,...

- Plain for a provisioning server, install the server, deploy service.
- Setup OS, configuring OS, optimize OS as a requirement of production.
- Monitoring and manage all system servers and infrastructure for Datacenter have more than 10.000 physical servers and about 3000 virtual machines

- Automation deploy OS via template by a bash shell script.
- Configure network and service as a request from system engineer of product.
- Build, monitoring, maintenance & operation camera system for DC. Use NAS technologies for storing data, backup, log, and monitoring.
- Optimize & operation an access control system for DC.
- Plain for optimizing and improve the system.
- Support product resolve and troubleshoot problems.
- Deploy some script automation by bash shell and python.
- Operation tool monitoring: cacti, checkMK, Zabbix, Splunk,....

Luu Trữ Số - 123HOST 04/2016 - 05/2018

IT System Support

Join support team, configuring, monitoring network and infrastructure for the system. Configuring the system, installing service as request.

- Support customer use service Domain/Hosting/Server/VPS and more related service. Troubleshooting problems of customers when use service.
- Customer consulting, install the service web app, mail server,.... in Linux operating system as required from customer.
- Configuring, manage, optimize server hosting: cPanel, DirectAdmin, Plesk,...
- Configuring, manage, optimize virtual systems: OpenVZ, VMware ESXi, Proxmox,...
- Research and propose solutions for optimizing and improve system hosting/VPS.
- Design, deploy and maintain web, mail, app service: LAMP stack, LEMP stack, Nginx reverse proxy, HAproxy, postfix dovecot, SquirrelMail, MDaemon,....
- Monitoring, administrating system server of customers in the datacenter.
- Operating system DDOS protection, load balancing: WAF, IP Filtering, proxy,...

Tâm Việt Dental Clinic 09/2015 - 08/2016

IT Helpdesk

Take on role IT helpdesk. Design and configuring the network, installing and maintaining server local. Install application for the user.

- Build, configuring, and installing local network system for clinic.
- Monitoring network for medical equipment.
- Administrating website system of clinic
- Report and propose solutions to replace hardware and maintenance IT devices.
- Configuring software in the medical device, server, and pc for the user.

KNOWLEDGE & SKILLS

	System / DevOps //
CI/CD	Jenkins CI/CD, Github action, Gitlab
Database	Mysql, sqlite3, MS SQL.
Automation tools	Vagant, Ansible.
Cluster	OpenShift, Kubenetes.
Cloud	AWS EC2/ EBS/ AMI.
Virtualization	OpenVZ, Proxmox, VMware Esxi, Virtualbox, Docker.
Scripting	Python, bash shell, awk, sed.
Monitoring	Cacti, Zabbix, CheckMK, Grafana/Prometheus, Cabot/Graphite.
	OS & Networking //
Mail server	Postfix, Mdeamon, Dovecot, squirrelmail.
Web server	

Apache, Nginx, Tomcat, HAproxy, Nginx reverse proxy.

Network	CCNA, OSI network layer, TCP/IP
Linux system	DHCP, DNS, NFS, FTP server, LEMP Stack, LAMP Stack, FreeIPA, PrivacyIdea, OpenLDAP bashshell, iptables/firewalld, troubleshoot.
Other System	CoreDNS + Etcd, Parse Server + Parse Dashboard.
CERTIFICATE	
Python foundation	
Cpanel	
IPv6 Certificate	
LPI 1&2. LPI Advance	
CCNA	

INTERESTS

- Researching open-source projects & new technologies.
- Repair and Restoration motor engine. Research about Engine.
 Playing billiards, Game MOBA, swimming, playing guitar, listening to music, etc.